National Broadcasting Company Radio Recordings 5146 AV
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
National Broadcasting Company Radio Recordings
1936-1949
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
National Broadcasting Company (NBC)
5146 AV
2 cubic feet
2 linear ft.
Speeches (documents).
Recordings of speeches, debates, discussions, reports and analyses aired on NBC radio.
2293655
General
Contact Information:
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives Martin P. Catherwood Library 227 Ives Hall Cornell University Ithaca, NY 14853 (607) 255-3183 kheel_center@cornell.edu http://www.ilr.cornell.edu/library/kheel-center
Compiled by:
Kheel Staff, November 16, 2012
EAD encoding:
Kheel Staff, March 07, 2019
Scope and Contents
Include the following: William Green addressing unemployment, employer opposition to unions, the National Labor Relations Board, communism, the right to organize, A.F. of L./CIO dual unionism, the Hitler-Stalin Pact, the European War, crisis in the CIO, A.F. of L. support of President Roosevelt's defense effort, opposition to the Burke-Wadsworth Military Conscription Bill, labor's defense policy, the Presidential election, 1940, appeal to workers to register with their state employment offices for defense work, and the Taft-Hartley Act.
Also, John L. Lewis discusses the political and economic state of the nation from the viewpoint of organized labor, the status of the CIO, the United Steelworkers organizing drive against Bethlehem Steel, the United Auto Workers drive in the aircraft industry, labor in defense, and the endorsement of Wendell Willkie in the presidential election, 1940.
Also, Daniel J. Tobin discusses the endorsement of Roosevelt for re-election, taxes, unemployment, national defense, attack on supporters of Wendell Willkie for president (1936, 1940); Thomas J. Lyons discusses the international crisis and its meaning for the New York State worker, and, labor's responsibility in the present crisis (1940-1941); George Meany discusses what the A.F. of L. means to the country, and the post-war economy -- prosperity or economic depression (1940-1944); Philip Murray discusses the unemployment census and argues for full employment and guaranteed annual wages for workers (n.d.).
Also, speeches by George Addes on the defense employment problem (1941); by George Berry on industrial problems (1936); by Lewis K. Comstock and Matthew Woll on cooperation between capital and labor (1938); a debate by Abram Flaxer, Walter Reuther and others on the question of the expulsion of the United Electrical, Radio, and Machine Workers of America from the CIO (1949); a commentary by Frank Murphy on the settlement of the General Motors Strike of 1937 (1937); a discussion by Rolland Thomas and others on the strike situation, charging that local communist leadership is behind wildcat strikes in North America (1941); a speech by Robert Wagner in which he speaks against Willkie and for the re-election of Roosevelt (1940); a rally speech by Henry Wallace in which he speaks on foreign policy and the war in Europe (1941); a seminar on national defense in which David Walsh was a participant (1940); speech by Burton K. Wheeler on then current issues facing Americans (1936); speech by John Winant defending the social security system against Republican criticism (1936); speech by Matthew Woll on unemployment (1940); and a speech by Walter Reuther, entitled, "Five hundred planes a day" (1940).
Conditions Governing Access
Access to the collections in the Kheel Center is restricted. Please contact a reference archivist for access to these materials.
Related Materials
Related Collections: /4039: Milton R. Konvitz Papers /4212: Kheel Center Current Documents Correspondence 5131: Sidney A. Wolff Arbitration Files 5315: NWLB Arbitration regarding Electrical Transcription Manufacturers and American Federation of Musicians 5318: NLRB Briefs, Petitions and other Legal Documents 5488 B: BRAC Records 5538: James C. Hill Arbitration Files 5539: Benjamin H. Wolf Additional Arbitration Files 5541: Philip Taft Papers 5571: Jacob Seidenberg Additional Arbitration Files 5581: New York State Board of Mediation Cases 5583/1: Archives Organization File (AOF) Part 1 5583/2: Archives Organization File (AOF) Part 2 5583/3: Archives Organization File (AOF) Part 3 5609: Philip Ross Collection of NLRB Documents 5637: Sidney A. Wolff Additional Arbitration Files 5712: Burton B. Turkus Arbitration Files 5733: Peter Seitz Arbitration Files 5761 mf: William Green Papers on Microfilm 5780 P N45: ILGWU 4x5 Negatives of Photographs 5956: Archives Organization File Additional records 6021/004: Theodore W. Kheel Legal Files 6046: Archives Union File (AUF) 6047: Archives Information File 6441: Sidney A. Wolff Collections
Burke-Wadsworth Military Conscription Bill.; Industry. Defense measures. United States.; Trade-unions. United States. Recognition.; General Motors Corporation Sit-Down Strike, 1936-1937.; Labor--United States--Political activity.; Working class--United States--Political activity.; Labor movement--United States--Political activity.; Draft--United States.; Presidents--United States--Election--1940.; Russo-German treaty, 1939.; Social security--United States.; Labor unions and communism--United States.; Labor unions and foreign policy--United States.; Unemployment--United States.; World War, 1939-1945--Economic aspects--United States.; World War, 1939-1945--Economic aspects--New York (State); United States. Defenses.; Bethlehem Steel Corporation; United Electrical, Radio, and Machine Workers of America; United States. Labor Management Relations Act, 1947; Bethlehem Steel Corporation.; International Union, United Automobile Workers of America (CIO); United Electrical, Radio, and Machine Workers of America; United States. National Labor Relations Board.; United Steelworkers of America; Addes, George P. 1910 -; Berry, George Leonard, 1882-1948; Flaxer, Abram, 1904-; Green, William, 1870-1952; Lyons, Thomas J.; Meany, George, 1894-1904; Murphy, Frank, 1890-1949; Murray, Philip, 1886-1952; Reuther, Walter, 1907-1970; Thomas, R. J. (Rolland Jay), 1900-1967; Tobin, Daniel J. (Daniel Joseph), 1875-1955; Wagner, Robert F. (Robert Ferdinand), 1877-1953; Wallace, Henry A. (Henry Agard), 1888-1965; Walsh, David I. (David Ignatius), 1872-1947; Willkie, Wendell L. (Wendell Lewis), 1892-1944; Winant, John G. (John Gilbert), 1889-1947; Woll, Matthew, 1880-1956; Comstock, Lewis K.
2293655
- George F. Addes, 1910-, George Meany (speakers), 1 (Box 1)
  Scope and Contents
  The Defense Unemployment Problem; Prosperity or Depression -- [11/29/1941, 11/10/1944]
- Thomas J. Mooney, George Meany, 1894- (speakers), 2 (Box 1)
  Summary of Pardon Hearings; What the AFL Means to the Country - [1/7/1939, 2/26, 1940]
- Lewis K. Comstock, 1865-, Matthew Woll, -1880 (speakers), 1938; 3 (Box 1)
  Discussion [8/2/1938]
- George Berry, 1882-, Burton K. Wheeler, 1882- (speakers), 1936; 4 (Box 1)
  Report; What is the Most Important Issue Facing America Today - [3/14/1936, 2/25, 1936]
- Thomas J. Lyons, Patterson, Robert P. -1891 (speakers), 1941; 5 (Box 1)
  Labor's Responsibility in the Present Crisis; Labor Pitches In - [8/19/1941, 8/20/1941]
- Thomas J. Lyons, 1940; 6 (Box 1)
  Speech [8/20/1940]
- William Green, 1873, 1938; 7 (Box 1)
  A Restatement of Labor's Aims and Purposes [9/5/1938]
- William Green, 1873-, 1938; 8 (Box 1)
- William Green, 1873-, 1939; 9 (Box 1)
  Speech [9/4/1939]
- Philip Murray, 1886-, William Green, 1873- (speakers), 10 (Box 1)
  The Unemployment Census; We Must Stay Out of It - [11/9/1937, 10/2/1939]
- William Green, 1873, 1941; 11 (Box 1)
  Labor and Registration for Defense; Labor, Education and Natl. Defense - [4/26/1941, 4/3/1941]
- William Green, 1873-, 1949; 12 (Box 1)
  Toryism [9/5/1949]
- William Green, 1873-, 1940; 13 (Box 1)
  Speech [9/2/1940]
- William Green, 1873-, 1940; 14 (Box 1)
  The Preservation of America [6/7/1940]
- William Green, 1873-, 1938; 15 (Box 1)
  Address [10/3/1938]
- William Green, 1873-, 1938; 16 (Box 1)
- Frank Murphy, Philip, Murray, -1886 (speakers), 17 (Box 1)
  commentary; Jobs for Everyone - [2/11/1937, 9/4/1944]
- John L. Lewis, 1880-, 1939; 18 (Box 1)
  Address [9/4/1939]
- John L. Lewis, 1880-, 1940; 19 (Box 1)
- John L. Lewis, 1880-, 1940; 20 (Box 1)
  Speech [10/25/1940]
- R.J. Thomas, Walter Reuther, and Richard Frankenstein, 1941; 21 (Box 1)
  Discussion [6/12/1941]
- Robert Wagner, 1877-, 1940; 22 (Box 1)
  Speech [10/30/1940]
- Henry Wallace, 1888-; David Dubinsky, 1941; 23 (Box 1)
  Rally Speech [10/31/1941]
- Abram Flaxer, 1904-; John G. Winant, 1889-, 24 (Box 1)
  Debate; Speech - [12/18/1949, 10/26/1936]
- Walter Reuther; Daniel Tobin, 25 (Box 1)
  500 Planes a Day; Speech [12/28/1940, 10/23/1936]
- David I. Walsh, 1872-, 1940; 26 (Box 1)
  National Defense Seminar [10/16/1940]
- Daniel J. Tobin, 1875-; Matthew Woll, 1880- (speakers), 1940; 27 (Box 1)
  Cooperation between Labor, Industry, and Government; Unemployment [5/13/1940, 1/22/1940]
- Daniel J. Tobin, 1875, 1940; 28 (Box 1)
  A Call to Labor [9/25/1940]
- Daniel J. Tobin, 1875-, 1940; 29 (Box 1)
  Speech [10/29/1940]
- Daniel J. Tobin, 1875-, 1940; 30 (Box 1)
- George F. Address, 1910-; George Meany, 1894- (speakers), 1 (Box 2)
  The Defense Unemployment Problem; prosperity or Depression - [11/29/1941, 11/10/1944]
- Thomas J. Mooney; George Meany, 1894- (speakers), 2 (Box 2)
  Summary of Pardon Hearings; What the AFL Means to the Country - [1/7/1939, 2/26/1940]
- Lewis K. Comstock, 1864-; Matthew Woll, -1880 (speakers), 1938; 3 (Box 2)
- George Berry, 1882-; Burton K. Wheeler, 1882- (speakers), 1936; 4 (Box 2)
- Thomas J. Lyons; Patterson, Robert p. -1891, 1941; 5 (Box 2)
  Labor's Responsibility in the Present Crisis; labor Pitches In - [8/19, 1941, 8/20/1941]
- Thomas J. Lyons, 1940; 6 (Box 2)
- William Green, 1873, 1938; 7 (Box 2)
  A Restatement of Labor's Aims and Purposes - [9/5/1938]
- William Green, 1873-, 1938; 8 (Box 2)
- William Green, 1873-, 1939; 9 (Box 2)
  Speech - [9/4/1939]
- Philip Murray, 1886-; William Green, 1873- (speakers), 10 (Box 2)
- William Green, 1873, 1941; 11 (Box 2)
- William Green, 1873-, 1949; 12 (Box 2)
  Toryism - [9/5/1949]
- William Green, 1873-, 1940; 13 (Box 2)
  Speech - [9/2/1940]
- William Green, 1873-, 1940; 14 (Box 2)
  The Preservation of America - [6/7/1940]
- William Green, 1873-, 1938; 15 (Box 2)
  Address - [10/3/1938]
- William Green, 1873-, 1938; 16 (Box 2)
- Frank Murphy; Philip, Murray, 1886-, 17 (Box 2)
  commentary; Jobs for Everyone - [2/11/1937; 9/4/1944]
- John L. Lewis, 1880-, 1939; 18 (Box 2)
  Address - [9/4/1939]
- John L. Lewis, 1880-, 1940; 19 (Box 2)
  Speech from Washington on Labor Day - [9/2/1940]
- John L. Lewis, 1880-, 1940; 20 (Box 2)
  Speech - [10/25/1940]
- R.J. Thomas, Walter Reuther, and Richard Frankenstein, 1941; 21 (Box 2)
  Discussion - [6/12/1941]
- Robert Wagner, 1877-, 1940; 22 (Box 2)
  Speech - [10/30/1940]
- Henry Wallace, 1888-, 1941; 23 (Box 2)
  Rally Speech - [10/31/1941]
- Abram Flaxer, 1904-; John G. Winant, 1889- (speakers), 24 (Box 2)
- Walter Reuther; Daniel Tobin (speakers), 25 (Box 2)
  500 Planes a Day; Speech - [12/28/1940, 10/23/1936]
- David I. Walsh, 1872-, 1940; 26 (Box 2)
  national Defense Seminar - [10/16/1940]
- Daniel J. Tobin, 1875-; Matthew Woll, 1880- (speakers), 1940; 27 (Box 2)
  Cooperation between Labor, Industry, and Government; Unemployment - [5/13/1940, 1/22/1940]
- Daniel J. Tobin, 1875, 1940; 28 (Box 2)
  A Call to Labor - [9/25/1940]
- Daniel J. Tobin, 1875-, 1940; 29 (Box 2)
  Speech - [10/29/1940]
- Daniel J. Tobin, 1875-, 1940; 30 (Box 2)